# **Vishal Kumar**

#### **Details**

Noida

India

+91-7783032013

kushwahavishal7783032013@gmail.com

### Languages

English

Hindi

#### **Hobbies**

Cricket, BGMI, Travelling

#### Skills

HTML & CSS

**JavaScript** 

CSS and JS

Wordpress

Canva

Photoshop

Logo

Instagram Ads

# **Project Link**

Messpe

Pappu Travels

Subh-Labh Travels

**Wave Travels** 

Murti Cabs

Dev Bhoomi

SK Seo Services

Yati Trans logistics

### **Profile**

Highly accomplished and user-focused Front-end Developer adept in collaborating with UX and design teams to plan the technical writing and execution of functional specifications for websites and applications. Experienced in building multi-platform websites using Responsive Web Design.

# **Employment History**

### Front End Developer, Internship, Noida

OCTOBER 2021 - MAY 2022

- · Design, develop, test and deploy design features in a timely manner.
- · Continually work to ensure the user experience determines design choices.
- · Work to achieve a balance between functional and aesthetic designs.
- Maintain brand consistency throughout the design process.
- · Apply engineering best practices.
- Work to solve complex challenges with the utilization of modern web application development processes and standard methodologies.
- · Create wireframes to illustrate advanced solutions for applications.

#### Front End Developer, Sasco Group, Noida

JUNE 2022 - MAY 2023

- · Made high level contributions to a team leading site optimizations.
- Worked with teams to solve issues and find and implement efficiencies.
- · Collaborated with product managers to design cutting edge features.
- · Worked to create tools that enhanced user interaction in any browser.
- Ensured the technology implemented promoted efficiency, speed, and smooth functionality.
- · Continually tested the site for usability while addressing any bugs.

## Education

B.sc - 2nd Pursuing, DDU Gorakhpur, Gorakhpur

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

12th, BSEB, Bihar

JANUARY 2018 - MARCH 2020

# Internships

Web & Graphic designer, Sasco Group, Noida

JUNE 2020 - MARCH 2021